## ARCHANA H NAIR

**Full Stack Developer** 

### **(** + 45 71451513

x archana.harinair@gmail.com

in linkedin.com/in/archana-h-nair-0b649922a/

github.com/archana6832

https://archana6832.github.io/Portfolio/

O Copenhagen , Denmark

#### **SUMMARY**

Full stack developer with a background in Engineering teaching and mentoring. Experienced in mentoring more than 15 groups of students in their Engineering final year projects and teaching more than 500 students throughout the career. Competent in creating websites and applications from concept, layout and interactive elements to server-side and databases. Skilled in the latest practices in web development (HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Redux, NodeJS).

#### **SKILLS**

#### **Front End Development**

- -HTML, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript
- -Libraries / Frameworks (React, Redux, Angular, Material, Bootstrap, SASS/SCSS, jQuery)
- -Responsive design, modals and touch interaction
- -AJAX & JSON
- -Version Control (Git)
- -unit testing, integration testing, acceptance testing, and end-to-end testing)
- -Mobile Apps (React Native, Expo, PWA)

#### **Back End Development**

- -NodeJS & Express
- -APIs (JSON, RESTful, Postman)
- -Hosting & Web Services (AWS, Google, Firestore, Heroku, Netlify)
- -Relational & non-relational databases (PostgreSQL, MongoDB)

#### **EDUCATION**

#### CareerFoundry

Full-Stack Development Program April 2021 - Feb 2022

#### **Speak School of Danish**

Danish Language Leanring
June 2018 - Dec 2019
B2 -Advanced Level

#### T K M College Of Engineering

Masters in Engineering & Technology August 2012 - Oct 2014 Second Rank in University

- published 3 papers in International journals.
- presented papers in 4 International conferences.

#### WEB DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

#### **CareerFoundry Project- Simple JS App**

- Created a JavaScript app built along with HTML, CSS, and ¡Query, which uses an external API.
- Implemented features according to guidelines set out by mock-ups and design assets.
- Utilized object-oriented programming (OOP) and functional programming (FP) principles to carry out application features.
   View App GitHub Repo

#### CareerFoundry Project - MyFlix React App

- Created a REST API with Node.js and Express.js and then used Mongoose to interact with a non-relational database (MongoDB) of movies stored as JSON objects.
- Tested the API with Postman, wrote clean and concise documentation for the endpoints, and deployed the API with Heroku.
- Built the application's client-side using React as a single-page, responsive application with routing, rich user interactions, several interface views, and a polished user experience.
   View App GitHub Repo

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Frontend Developer - Internship May 2022 - Present GreenCar Lane, Copenhagen, Denmark

- · Developing user interface for B2G clients.
- Coordinate and support with UI/UX team.
- Test software to ensure responsiveness and efficiency.

# **Assistant Professor** May 2010 - Nov 2011 **Atharva College of Engineering, Mumbai, India**

- Planned teaching methodologies effectively and assured 85% passing yearly.
- Mentored students in their projects and ensured the submission on time.
- Assisted Head of Department, achieved better performance of students by introducing new teaching plan.